FREDERICK JACKSON

San Antonio, TX 78216

duecefj88@gmail.com

210-955-3214

Hardworking General Laborer with several years in warehouse, production and manufacturing roles. Skilled in forklift operations, equipment repair and maintenance with high focus on quality and safety. Collaborates with team members to support operation with goal of increasing productivity and decreasing downtime and waste.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer



WORK EXPERIENCE -----

General Laborer

TX - San Antonio, TX March 2019 to July 2020

Sorted and placed materials or items on racks, shelves or in bins to keep warehouse organized.

Packaged and stored food products appropriately to ensure proper handling and preservation.

Re-stocked, organized and arranged service and food stations.

Maintained clean and sanitized work area in accordance with food safety guidelines, avoiding cross-contamination of raw and prepared food products.

Prepared for busy periods by organizing ingredients and restocking supplies for expected loads.

Followed recipes and customer request details to prepare high-quality, delicious meals.

Earned reputation for good attendance and hard work.

Worked closely with team members to deliver project requirements, develop solutions and meet deadlines.

Demonstrated self-reliance by meeting and exceeding workflow needs.

General Laborer

Yu got it staffing - San Antonio, TX

December 2019 to February 2020

Collaborated with team members to complete orders and meet tight deadlines.

Sorted and placed materials or items on racks, shelves or in bins to keep warehouse organized.

Read written instructions carefully and communicated with team members clearly to promote workplace safety.

Adhered to all OSHA operating and safety standards and company policies, rules, regulations and procedures.

Reported safety violations to supervisor to reduce risks and accidents.

Packaged and stored food products appropriately to ensure proper handling and preservation.

Re-stocked, organized and arranged service and food stations.

Maintained clean and sanitized work area in accordance with food safety guidelines, avoiding cross-contamination of raw and prepared food products.

Employed knowledge of cutlery and culinary tools to prepare and serve food orders.

Monitored and recorded temperatures of food, storage, and service areas to maintain established, regulatory guidelines.

Protected food from spoilage by properly storing in freezer and refrigerator.

Verified proper operation of refrigerators, freezers and warming lamps by collecting temperature readings every day.

Followed recipes and customer request details to prepare high-quality, delicious meals.

Added garnishes and other finishing touches to improve plating presentation.

Demonstrated self-reliance by meeting and exceeding workflow nee

Albriecht and son's construction - Marion, TX

September 2017 to May 2018

Carpenter

Built wood structures on previously poured foundation.

Cut timber, panels and other wooden materials according to measured dimensions.

Selected lumber based on particular species, characteristics, size, applications and applicable adhesives.

Prepared, cut and installed custom cabinetry, built-in bookcases and staircases.

Shaped materials to exact measurements for job requirements using hand tools and power equipment.

Organized assigned tasks for completion on individual and team levels.

Installed building structures such as windows, trim and cabinetry alone or with assistants to meet job deadlines.

Shift Leader

Jim N Nicks Bar-B-Q - Hiram, GA

June 2013 to February 2017

Trained and supervised team members to maximize performance and meet daily objectives.

Monitored employee performance and conducted retraining to correct problems and optimize productivity.

Coordinated with internal departments to maximize operational efficiency across production and administrative areas.

Upheld company standards and compliance requirements for operations and cleanliness of all areas.

Managed and mentored several staff members.

Oversaw schedules, accepted time off requests and found coverage for shifts.

Complied with all company safety procedures, policies and regulations to promote safe working environment.

Allocated tasks to employees daily and monitored activity and task completion.

Documented daily production levels, materials used and special incidents to keep management informed of all activities.

Coached and trained employees and created daily work schedules and assignments, boosting efficiency and enhancing operations.

Reviewed applicant resumes and recommended top candidates for hiring.

Ran daily reports to assess performance and make proactive adjustments.

Assisted with performance reviews to identify areas of improvement and devise proactive approaches.

Participated in daily shift exchanges to coordinate tasks and handled special needs.

Trained and supervised staff members.

Mentored team members on techniques necessary to complete job tasks.

Increased overall team efficiency and productivity.

Positioned skilled staff in key areas throughout shift to guarantee optimal productivity of overall department.

Helped employees operate productively and stay on task to meet business and customer needs.

Mentored and supported new employees to maximize team performance.



EDUCATION

Some college in Business Administration

Everest Institute - Atlanta, GA October 2011 to October 2012



SKILLS

Quality control
 Staff training and development Inspections
 Safety procedures
 Safety protocol

Janitorial tasks

Standard operating procedures understanding

Forklift driving

Materials handling

- Carpentry
- Culinary Experience
- Drywall
- Food Production
- Handyman
- Trim Carpentry
- Landscape Maintenance
- Remodeling
- Construction
- Door Hanging
- Supervising Experience
- Roofing
- Shift Management



ASSESSMENTS

Food Safety — Expert

March 2020

Proper food handling, storage, and equipment use for preventing the spread of foodborne illness.

Full results: Expert

Work Style: Reliability — Highly Proficient

February 2020

Tendency to be dependable and come to work.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Cleaner Fit — Proficient

August 2020

Measures the traits that are important for successful cleaners.

Full results: Proficient

Customer Focus & Orientation — Highly Proficient

March 2020

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Basic Maintenance and Repair — Highly Proficient

March 2020

Performing basic repairs and maintenance for apartment complexes, office buildings, and other facilities.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Memorization — **Proficient**

March 2020

Committing product or merchandise information to memory and recalling it at a later time.

Full results: Proficient

Attention to Detail — Completed

May 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: Completed

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.